Finding Aid for the Edwin Bower Hesser Papers LSC.1071
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Prints, ca. 1920-1945; 6 boxes, 19 oversize boxes
  - C. Small black and white, ca. 1925-1945
    - Book of dance poses, ca. 1920-1935; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 2)
      9 x 12" homemade book of black and white photographs featuring nude and semi-nude women models in various dance poses.
    - Carroll, Earl, ca. 1925-1935; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      6.5 x 8.5" black and white portrait of a man in formal attire.
    - Children (1 of 2), ca. 1935-1945; 18 items. (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified young boys and girls.
    - Children (2 of 2), ca. 1935-1945; 38 items. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Couples, ca. 1935-1945; 33 items. (Box 23, Folder 6)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits of couples in different poses.
    - Fairbanks [?], ca. 1925-1935; 8 items. (Box 23, Folder 7)
      6.5 x 8.5" black and white portraits of a woman in various poses in various attire. Back of some of photographs say "Fairbanks."
    - Hesser Studio Storefront, ca. 1940-1950; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 8)
      8 x 10" black and white exterior shot of Edwin Bower Hesser's photography studio
    - Hesser, Eve, ca. 1930-1940; 26 items. (Box 23, Folder 9)
      Various size black and white portraits.
    - Higby, ca. 1925-1935; 10 items. (Box 23, Folder 10)
      5 x 8" black and white portraits of a woman with curly hair.
    - Men--casual attire, ca. 1940-1945; 9 items. (Box 23, Folder 11)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits of men in casual attire.
    - Men--costume and festive attire, ca. 1925-1945; 16 items. (Box 23, Folder 12)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits of men in costumes and festive attire.
    - Men--formal attire, ca. 1940-1945; 52 items. (Box 23, Folder 13)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified men in formal attire (coat and tie).
    - Men--military uniforms, ca. 1935-1945; 11 item. (Box 23, Folder 14)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified men in military uniforms.
    - Miscellaneous Subjects, ca. 1925-1945; 33 items. (Box 23, Folder 15)
      Various sizes of black and white shots of miscellaneous subjects such as architecture and dupes of travel photos.
    - Outdoor scenes and trees, ca. 1935-1945; 87 items. (Box 23, Folder 16)
      Various sizes of black and white shots of various outdoor scenes and trees.
    - Photographs not shot by Hesser, ca. 1935-1950; 38 items. (Box 50, Folder 1)
      Various sizes of black and white headshots and portraits of models and children shot by other photographers and submitted to Hesser.
    - Tests--contact sheets, ca. 1930-1945; 35 items. (Box 50, Folder 2)
      Various sizes of black and white contact sheets from 4 x 5" negatives.
    - Tests--contact sheets of negatives (1 of 2), ca. 1930-1945; 85 items. (Box 50, Folder 3)
      8 x 10" black and white contact sheets of 4 x 5" negatives. Sheets are negative black and white values.
    - Tests--contact sheets of negatives (2 of 2), ca. 1930-1945; 29 items. (Box 50, Folder 4)
      9 x 10" black and white contact sheets of 4 x 5" negatives. Sheets are negative black and white values.
    - Tests--Hessercolor black and white values, ca. 1932-1943; 22 items. (Box 50, Folder 5)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits from 3 color Hessercolor negatives.
    - Tests--Retouching notes on contact prints, ca. 1930-1945; 6 items. (Box 50, Folder 6)
      4 x 5" black and white contact prints with Hesser's retouching notes.
    - Tests-still life, ca. 1930-1940; 7 items. (Box 50, Folder 7)
      Various sizes of black and white photographs of still life and paintings
    - Theatrical and film scenes, ca. 1930-1940; 11 item. (Box 50, Folder 8)
      Various sizes of black and white photographs of various unidentified theatrical and film productions.
    - Wilson, Margaret, ca. 1925-1935; 6 items. (Box 50, Folder 9)
      4 x 5" black and white portraits of President Woodrow Wilson's daughter.
    - Women--bed and couch scenes modeling (1 of 2), ca. 1925-1945; 23 items. (Box 50, Folder 10)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified women posing while laying on a bed or couch.
    - Women--bed and couch scenes modeling (2 of 2), ca. 1925-1945; 40 items. (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Women--casual attire, ca. 1935-1945; 76 items. (Box 51, Folder 1)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified women in casual attire, such as sweaters, blouses, and dresses.
    - Women--close-ups, ca. 1935-1945; 24 items. (Box 51, Folder 2)
      Various sizes of black and white close-up portraits of women in various poses.
    - Women--dance modeling, ca. 1935-1945; 15 items. (Box 51, Folder 3)
      Various sizes of black and white action shots of unidentified women dancing.
    - Women--exterior modeling (1 of 2), ca. 1935-1945; 60 items. (Box 51, Folder 4)
      Various sizes of black and white portrait shots of women modeling outdoors. Framed in medium and long shots.
    - Women--exterior modeling (2 of 2), ca. 1935-1945; 33 items. (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling (1 of 3), ca. 1925-1945; 21 item. (Box 51, Folder 6)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits and head shots of women modeling ruffled, low cut, and strapless attire. Includes shots of women in Latin-inspired dress and women in various costumes.
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling (2 of 3), ca. 1925-1945; 22 items. (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling (3 of 3), ca. 1925-1945; 32 items. (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Women--formal attire, ca. 1935-1945; 44 items. (Box 51, Folder 9)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits and head shots of women in formal attire, such as furs and gowns.
    - Women--hats, veils, and headwear modeling, ca. 1935-1945; 19 items. (Box 51, Folder 10)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits and head shots of women modeling hats, veils, or other types of headwear.
    - Women--interior modeling, ca. 1935-1945; 11 item. (Box 52, Folder 1)
      Various sizes of black and white portrait shots of women modeling various clothes indoors. All shots framed in medium and long or long shots.
    - Women--props modeling (1 of 2), ca. 1925-1945; 20 items. (Box 52, Folder 2)
      Various sizes of black and white portrait shots of women modeling with various props. Includes shots of women modeling with flowers, fruit, house ware, and art props.
    - Women--props modeling (2 of 2), ca. 1925-1945; 25 items. (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Women--semi-formal and business attire, ca. 1935-1945; 48 items. (Box 52, Folder 4)
      Various sizes of black and white portraits and head shots of women in semi-formal and business attire, such as blouses, dresses, and suits.
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, erotic attire modeling (1 of 7), ca. 1920-1945; 46 items. (Box 52, Folder 5)
      Various sizes of black and white portrait shots of women modeling semi-nude, nude, and in lingerie, erotic, and revealing attire.
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, erotic attire modeling (2 of 7), ca. 1920-1945; 45 items. (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, erotic attire modeling (3 of 7), ca. 1920-1945; 40 items. (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, erotic attire modeling (4 of 7), ca. 1920-1945; 54 items. (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, erotic attire modeling (5 of 7), ca. 1920-1945; 33 items. (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, erotic attire modeling (6 of 7), ca. 1920-1945; 23 items. (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, erotic attire modeling (7 of 7), ca. 1920-1945; 52 items. (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric (1 of 3), ca. 1920-1940; 27 items. (Box 53, Folder 1)
      Various sizes of black and white portrait shots of naked or semi-nude women wrapped in mesh or fabric.
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric (2 of 3), ca. 1920-1940; 26 items. (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric (3 of 3), ca. 1920-1940; 37 items. (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - D. Small Hessercolor, ca. 1932-1943
    This subseries consists of smaller format prints of Edwin Bower Hesser's color process known as Hessercolor. The photographs feature women, men, and children in casual, semi-formal, and formal attire; nude, semi-nude, and erotic modeling women; women in costume and festive attire; various animals; women in bathing suits; women in winter clothes; men in military uniforms; couples; models with various props; various exterior scenes; theatrical and film scenes; and women dancing. Files are arranged alphabetically according to subject.
    - Buildings and aerial shots, ca. 1932-1943; 2 items. (Box 53, Folder 4)
      Various sizes of Hessercolor prints of a building an aerial shot.
    - Hesser, Eve, ca. 1932-1943; 10 items. (Box 53, Folder 5)
      Various sizes of Hessercolor portraits.
    - Incomplete Hessercolor prints, ca. 1932-1943; 13 items. (Box 53, Folder 6)
      Various sizes of incomplete Hessercolor prints, consisting of gelatin transparencies and single color layer prints.
    - Men--uniforms, ca. 1932-1943; 2 items. (Box 53, Folder 7)
      8 x 10" Hessercolor portrait shots of outside in uniform.
    - Still life, ca. 1932-1943; 7 items. (Box 53, Folder 8)
      Various sizes of Hessercolor prints of objects such as plates of food, dresses, and flowers.
    - Theatrical and film scenes, ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 53, Folder 9)
      Various sizes of Hessercolor prints of various unidentified theatrical and film productions.
    - Women--casual attire, ca. 1932-1943; 18 items. (Box 53, Folder 10)
      Various sizes of Hessercolor portraits and head shots of unidentified women in casual attire, such as sweaters, blouses, and dresses.
    - Women--exterior modeling, ca. 1932-1943; 3 items. (Box 53, Folder 11)
      8 x 10" Hessercolor portrait shots of women modeling outdoors. Framed in medium and long shots.
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling, ca. 1932-1943; 12 items. (Box 54, Folder 1)
      8 x 10" Hessercolor portraits and head shots of women modeling ruffled, low cut, and strapless attire. Includes shots of women in Latin-inspired dress and women in various costumes.
    - Women--formal attire, ca. 1932-1943; 7 items. (Box 54, Folder 2)
      Various sizes of Hessercolor portraits and head shots of women in formal attire, such as furs and gowns.
    - Women--hats, veils, and headwear modeling (1 of 2), ca. 1932-1943; 17 items. (Box 54, Folder 3)
      Various sizes of Hessercolor portraits and head shots of women modeling hats, veils, or other types of headwear.
    - Women--hats, veils, and headwear modeling (2 of 2), ca. 1932-1943; 10 items. (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Women--props modeling, ca. 1932-1943; 15 items. (Box 54, Folder 5)
      Various sizes of Hessercolor portrait shots of women modeling with various props. Includes shots of women modeling with flowers, fruit, house ware, and art props.
    - Women--semi-formal and business attire, ca. 1932-1943; 7 items. (Box 54, Folder 6)
      Various sizes of Hessercolor portraits and head shots of women in semi-formal and business attire, such as blouses, dresses, and suits.
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, erotic attire modeling, ca. 1932-1943; 8 items. (Box 54, Folder 7)
      Various sizes of Hessercolor portrait shots of women modeling semi-nude, nude, and in lingerie, erotic, revealing attire.
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric, ca. 1932-1943; 17 items. (Box 54, Folder 8)
      Various sizes of Hessercolor portrait shots of naked or semi-nude women wrapped in mesh or fabric.